Murray Forman Collection of Hip Hop Magazines, 1978-2007 SC 139
Archives of African American Music and Culture
Murray Forman Collection of Hip Hop Magazines
1978-2007
Archives of African American Music and Culture
Forman, Murray
SC 139
18 document cases 14.75 linear feet
1 Audio File digital
Magazines and articles collected by Murray Forman during research for his book, The 'Hood Comes First: Race, Space, and Place in Rap and Hip-Hop (Wesleyan University, 2002).
Arrangement
Arranged in three series:
Series 1: Magazines (alphabetical by publication title, then chronological)
Series 2: Articles
Series 3: Interview
Biographical / Historical
Murray Forman, a media studies and culture scholar, received his PhD in Communication Studies from McGill University and is a significant contributor to hip hop scholarship. His first book, The 'Hood Comes First: Race, Space and Place in Rap and Hip-Hop, was published in 2002. He also edited That's the Joint!: The Hip-Hop Studies Reader (Routledge, 2004) and authored One Night on TV is Worth Weeks at the Paramount: Popular Music on Early Television (Duke University Press, 2012). Forman was an inaugural recipient of the Nasir Jones Hip-Hop Fellowship at the Hip-Hop Archive, the Hutchins Center for African and African American research, Harvard University for the year of 2014-2015. He is currently professor of Media and Screen Studies at Northeastern University.
Access Restrictions
Use of time-based media materials (audio and video) may require production of listening or viewing copies.
Access to streaming audio, moving image, and full resolution digital image materials may currently be restricted to researchers who can authenticate with an IU account or who are physically present on campus. Remote streaming to individual researchers may be allowed with the completion of applicable forms.
For further information about access to online audiovisual materials, contact AAAMC staff at aaamc@indiana.edu.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Murray Forman in 2007.
Related Materials
AAAMC Liner Notes, no. 12 (Winter 2007)
Additional issues of Rap Pages, Rap Sheet, and XXL are available in AAAMC general periodical collection.
Scope and Contents
Magazines and articles collected by Murray Forman during research for his book, The 'Hood Comes First: Race, Space, and Place in Rap and Hip-Hop (Wesleyan University, 2002). Series 1 contains hip hop periodicals and feature articles published from 1989-2006, including a nearly complete run of The Source, as well as various issues of Blaze, Hip-Hop Connection, Hip-Hop Weekly, Rap Masters, Rap Pages, Rap Sheet, Rappin', Spin, Vibe, and XXL. Also included are articles related to hip hop from mainstream magazines such as Ebony, Forbes, Newsweek, Rolling Stone, and Time. The summaries of the content and featured artists are meant to provide a broad overview for research purposes and should not be considered a complete index of the contents. Series 2 includes Billboard Chart Ratings from 1978-1998.
Separated Materials
Serial titles with more than six issues may have been have been transferred to the AAAMC's general periodical collection.
Rap (Music)--Periodicals; Hip-hop--Periodicals; Rap musicians--Periodicals; Rap musicians; Rap (Music)--History and criticism; Rhythm and blues musicians; Reggae musicians; African American actors; African American musicians; African American sound recording executives and producers; Sound recording industry--United States--Periodicals; Popular culture--History--20th century--Periodicals; Popular music--1991-2000; Periodicals
- 1. Magazines, 1989-2006; 16 Boxes
  - 2 Hype (vol. 1, no. 1), 1990 December (Box 1)
    General
    Big Daddy Kane, LL Cool J, Rap's Hypeople, D-Nice, YZ, Tashan, New Edition, BBD, Fresh Prince of Bel Air, In Living Color, Females of Rap, Michael Concepcion, Run DMC.
  - Beat Down (vol. 5, no. 6), 1997 (Box 1)
    Jay-Z
    Jay-Z, Wu-Tang Clan, Common, RBL Posse, EPMD, Diamond D, Shaggy, DJ King Britt (aka Sylk 130), Crooked Lettaz, Organized Konfusion, Mood, Jigmastas, II Tru, Vooodu, Shaggy, Erick Sermon.
  - Beat Down (vol. 6, no. 1), 1997 (Box 1)
    Mase and Sean Puffy Combs
    Rakim, H-Town, Busta Rhymes, Mystikal, Mic Geronimo, Salt-N-Peppa, British soul singer Ali, Puerto Rican songstress Veronica, Hurricane G, Puff Daddy.
  - Billboard, 1991 April 13 (Box 1)
    Contents: Rap music has the blues as KDAY L.A. calls it quits / Craig Rosen and Janine McAdams -- NARAS panel probes racism in Music Biz / David Nathan.
  - Black Beat (vol. 21, no. 6), 1990 June (Box 1)
    Janet Jackson, Bobby Brown, Regina Belle, Chuckii Booker, Big Daddy Kane, Paula Abdul, Everlast, Maze, MC Hammer, Nice & Smooth, MC Lyte, Ice-T.
  - Black Beat (vol. 21, no. 10), 1990 October (Box 1)
    LL Cool J, Bobby Brown, Salt-N-Peppa, Milira, Paula Abdul, Keith Sweat, Kid-N-Play, Digital Underground, Big Daddy Kane, Fast Eddie & Joe Smooth.
  - Black Enterprise (vol. 30, no. 5), 1999 (Box 1)
    Puffy & Master P.
    Hip-Hop Moguls: Beyond the Hype / Tariq K. Muhammad.
  - Black Enterprise (vol. 32, no. 10), 2002 (Box 1)
    Damon Dash and Jay-Z
    Hip Hop Economy, part 1 /Alan Hughes.
  - Black Enterprise (vol. 32, no. 12), 2002 (Box 1)
    Hip Hop Economy, part 2: Hip-Hop at the Movies /Sakina P. Spruell -- Tech Rocks (Chuck D and Nile Rogers) / Holly Aguirre.
  - Black Enterprise (vol. 33, no. 1), 2002 (Box 1)
    Hip Hop Economy, part 3: Music Masters / Shawn E. Rhea.
  - Black Sounds, 1990 June (Box 1)
    Chuckii Booker, Young MC, Heavy D & The Boyz, Angela Winbush, O'Jay's, Levert, Arabian Prince, 2 Live Crew, Troop, Donald D, M.C. Hammer, Bobby Brown, Randy & The Gypsys (Randy Jackson), Paula Abdul, Big Daddy Kane, Soul II Soul, Little Richard, Wrecks-N-Effect, DJ Russ Parr (KJMZ), James "JT" Taylor, Surface.
  - Black Sounds, 1990 September (Box 1)
    Janet Jackson Rhythm Nation tour, Chuckii Booker, Above the Law, Earth, Wind & Fire, Michel'le, Rap sampling, Calloway Brothers, Digital Underground, Def Jeff, Queen Latifah, Tony! Toni! Tone!, D.J. Jazzy Jeff and The Fresh Prince, Bell Biv DeVoe, Jungle Brothers, Smokey Robinson, Michael Jeffreys, Tone Loc.
  - Black Sounds, 1990 November (Box 1)
    Johnny Gill, Tairrie B, Silk Tymes Leather, Keith Sweat, Lisa Stanfield, 2 Live Crew, Klymaxx, ice Cube, Howard Hewett, Boo-Yaa T.R.I.B.E., Public Enemy, Family Stand, Bobby Brown, Kwame, Heavy D, M.C. Hammer, L.L. Cool J.
  - Blaze, 1998 Fall (Box 2)
    Method Man
    Method Man, Snoop Dogg, Ras Kass, Xzibit, Outkast, Noreaga, Black Star, dubplate, KRS-One, E-40, Lil'Kim, Fat Joe, DMX, ONYX.
  - Blaze, 1999 May (Box 2)
    DMX
    Hip hop behind bars, Eightball & MJG, Rah Digga, Charli Baltimore, Nature.
  - Blaze, 2000 March (Box 2)
    Drag-On
    Drag-On, Juvenile, Young Bleed, Trick Daddy, Drama, Kurupt, Notorious B.I.G., Prestige, DJ Skribble, Tha Eastsidaz, Spring fashion, bootlegging, Jay-Z, Lance "Un" Rivera.
  - Doula: The Journal of Rap and Hip Hop Culture (vol. 1, no. 1), 2000 Fall (Box 2)
    Intro / Harry Allen -- Hip Hop: Cultural to Corporate Entertainment / April R. Silver -- Myth of Multiculturalism in Hip Hop's Early Days / Davey D -- Poems: Caught Up and Culture Shock / Tammy Chrystell -- A Semiotic Analysis of the Rap Lyrics of "Big Poppa" / Chic Smith -- Rap: The New Blues? / Yvonne Bynoe -- Salt-N-Pepa, Lil' Kim, Foxy Brown and Eve: The Politics of the Female Body / Wanda Renee Porter -- A Working Hip Hop Chronology / Russell A. Potter.
  - Details (The Music Issue), 1992 July (Box 2)
    Magic Mountain / Brian Cullman -- Deee-Lite Stuff / Erik Hedegaard -- The Prehistory of Rock 'n' Roll / Robert Christgau -- Making a Scene: Memphis 1956-74 / Robert Gordon -- Q&A: Pauly Shore -- Head Trip (the Cure's Robert Smith) / Chris Heath -- Q&A: Annie Lenox -- The Techno Revolution / Simon Reynolds.
  - Details, 1993 July (Box 2)
    Digible Planets
    Rock 'n' Roll High / Larry Gallagher -- Get Your Kicks / Kevin Cook -- Cool Like Us (Digable Planets) / Pat Blashill -- Evan Dando -- Grunge -- Buddha of Suburbia (Rick Rubin) / RJ Smith -- Boy George -- Progressive Rock -- New Wave Wipeout / Martin Aston -- Robert Plant -- Ambient Music -- Crib Notes -- Tom Jones.
  - Details, 1998 November (Box 2)
    Lauryn Hill
    40 Records That Shook the World / Will Hernes -- Good Vibrations (Janet Jackson) -- God Save the Scene (Chemical Brothers) -- Bay City Roller (Stephan Jenkins) -- Wok 'n' Roll (China's punk youth) -- Georgia on my Mind (Athens, GA) -- Big Beat Masala (Talvin Singh) -- Twin City Tycoon (Prince) / Greg Kot -- Nordic Tracks (Nina Persson) -- Indy Spirit (John Mellencamp) -- Sabbath Night Fever (Dana International) -- Desert Fever (Ken Jordan) -- Canadian Hams (Barenaked Ladies).
  - DJ: Dance Music and Clubs Explained and Explored (no. 66), 1992 April (Box 2)
    Brand New Heavies
    Brand New Heavies, C&C Music Factory, Jazzie B.
  - DJ: Dance Music and Clubs Explained and Explored (no. 68), 1992 June (Box 2)
    Arrested Development
    Arrested Development, Disco, Mayday.
  - DJ: Dance Music and Clubs Explained and Explored (no. 12), 1998 April (Box 2)
    The Hot 100
  - Ear, 1990 March (Box 3)
    Queen Latifah
    Fight the Power: Women Rappers / Jennifer Massalon and Marie Elsie St. Leger
  - Ebony, 1996 August (Box 3)
    Will Smith
    Will Smith, Oleta Adams
  - Ebony, 2001 January (Box 3)
    Master P, Russell Simmons, Sean Puffy Combs
    CEO$ of Hip Hop and the Billion-Dollar Jackpot / Kevin Chappell.
  - Ebony, 2003 June (Box 3)
    Bernie Mac
    L.A. Reid: The Most Powerful Black in the Music Business / Lynn Norment.
  - The Fever: Literary Essence of Hip-Hop (no. 3), 1994 July/August (Box 3)
    KRS-One
  - The Flavor: A Real Hip-Hop Magazine (no. 21), 1994 December (Box 3)
    Tha Alkaholiks
    Keith Murray, Brand Nubian, Alkaholiks, Pete Rock & CL Smooth, Jemini.
  - Forbes, 1999 March 22 (Box 3)
    Puff Daddy and Jerry Seinfeld, Celebrity 100: Star Power, Star Brands.
  - Gear (The Hip Hop Issue), 2002 March (Box 3)
    Damon Dash, Cashun and gay rappers, Suge Knight.
  - Hip-Hop Connection, 1992 April (Box 4)
    Gang Starr
  - Hip-Hop Connection, 1992 May (Box 4)
    Pete Rock and CL Smooth
  - Hip-Hop Connection, 1993 July (Box 4)
    Paris
  - Hip-Hop Connection, 1993 August (Box 4)
    Ice T
  - Hip-Hop Connection, 1993 December (Box 4)
    Luther Campbell
  - Hip-Hop Connection, 1994 April (Box 4)
    Snoop Doggy Dogg
  - Hip-Hop Weekly (vol. 1, no. 2), 2006 December (Box 4)
  - High Times, 1993 March (Box 4)
    Redman
  - Hit the Decks (vol. 72, no. 7), 1992 August (Box 4)
    Jimmy Jam & Terry Lewis
  - Mad (no. 406), 2001 June (Box 4)
    Slim Shady (Eminem)
  - Mixtape (vol. 1, no. 2) (Collector's Edition), 2004 (Box 4)
    DJ Whoo Kid
  - Mother Jones (vol. 15, no. 6), 1990 September/October (Box 4)
    Salt-N-Pepper
  - Music Technology (vol. 5, no. 1), 1990 December (Box 4)
    Stereo MCs
  - New York Times Magazine, 1996 January 14 (Box 4)
    Tupac Shakur, Suge Knight, Snoop Doggy Dogg
    Does a Sugar Bear Bite? Suge Knight and his Posse / Lynn Hirschberg.
  - Newsweek, 1990 March 19 (Box 4)
    Tone-Lōc
    Rap Rage
  - Newsweek, 1992 June 29 (Box 4)
    Sister Souljah
    Rap and Race
  - Newsweek, 1993 November 29 (Box 4)
    When is Rap 2 Violent?
  - Newsweek, 2000 October 9 (Box 4)
    Eminem and Dr. Dre
    The Rap on Rap
  - Pulse, 1992 August (Box 4)
    Chuck D, KRS-One, EPMD
  - Pulse, 1994 August (Box 4)
    Public Enemy
  - Rap Masters, 1990 May (Box 5)
    Donald D., K-YZE, Doctor Ice, Funtime rap, EPMD, Clubhouse rappers, Political rappers, Gangster rappers, Heavy D, Public Enemy, Kid 'N Play, Queen Latifah, N.W.A., Special Ed, 3rd Bass, Big Daddy Kane, MC Lyte, Biz Markie.
  - Rap Masters, 1990 September (Box 5)
    Doug E. Fresh, D-Nice, Biz Markie, KRS-One, L.L. Cool J, Ice-Cube, Public Enemy, X-Clan, Humpty Hump, MC Hammer, Greg Nice, MC Lyte, Kid 'N Play, Flavor Flav, Above the Law, Prof. Griff & The Last Asiatic Disciples, King Sun, Nice 'N' Smooth, Shinehead.
  - Rap Masters, 1990 December (Box 5)
    East Meets West: A Special Rap Report (with poster), Mellow Man Ace, Kool G. Rap & DJ Polo, Antoinette, Above the Law, Silk Tymes Leather, Three Times Dope, Master Ace, New Jack City, Ice-T, Monie Love, The Afros.
  - Rap Masters, 1991 February (Box 5)
    Big Daddy Kane, Doug E. Fresh, KRS-One, Father MC, The Jaz, Run-DMC, EPMD, Kool G. Rap & DJ Polo, Females respond to sexism in rap.
  - Rap Masters, 1991 March (Box 5)
    Monie Love, Vanilla Ice, X-Clan, Young Black Teenagers, N.W.A., Chubb Rock, Candyman, Big Daddy Kane, KRS-One, Ice Cube, Run-DMA & Jam Master Jay, Father MC.
  - Rap Masters, 1991 April (Box 5)
    Yo-Yo, N.W.A., Brand Nubian, Paris, MC Twist, Rap's 25 Most Hardcore (with poster), EPMD, N.W.A., Rap's Battle of the Sexes, MC Twist, Heavy D, Queen Latifah.
  - Rap Masters, 1991 May (Box 5)
    Vanilla Ice, Rap's Greatest MCs, Hip-Hop Queens, The Rise of Hip House, Rap's White Wave, Political Rappers, Gang Starr, BWP, Too Short, L.L. Cool J, N.W.A., Ice-Cube, Grandaddy I.U.
  - Rap Masters, 1991 September (Box 5)
    Slick Rick, Heavy D, The Genius, Kool Moe Dee, KRS-One, Leaders of the New School, DJ Magic Mike, DJ Quik, 3rd Bass, Ice-T, L.A.'s Hardcore (with poster), Rap Tackles Police Brutality.
  - Rap Masters, 1993 January (Box 5)
    L.L. Cool J, Daddy Freddy, Soldiers for Christ (SFC), 1992 Hip-Hop Review, Kriss Kross, Monie Love, Super Cat.
  - Rappin, 1990 July (Box 5)
    Women of Rap: Queen Latifah, Roxanne Shante, MC Lyte, Neneh Cherry, Darlene (Rhyme Syndicate), Sweet L.D. from Oaktown 3.5.7., Body and Soul, Real Roxanne, Sweet Tee, Salt-N-Pepa, Antoinette (Lovell Patterson), Cookie Crew.
  - Rappin, 1991 January (Box 5)
    Outlaws of Rap: Public Enemy, Just Ice, Lyrics Get a Legal Rap, Cheba, Ice Cube, NWA, Afrika Islam, Ice-T, Eazy-E.
  - Request, 1994 August (Box 5)
    Warren G
    Warren G - King of the Pacific Coast Highway, Nu Soul Habits, Rap and La Raza (La Familia), Prince.
  - Right On!, 1990 October (Box 5)
    BBD
    Redhead Kingpin, Bell Biv Devoe, Michel'le, Troop, Partners in Kryme, M.C. Hammer, Howard Hewett, Billy Ocean, M.C. Trouble, Kim Wayans, Cameo, Salt-N-Pepa, In Living Color, New Jack City, Christopher Willias, Lisa Stanfield, Nice and Smooth, Newkirk, Kadeem Hardison, California rappers unite to lessen gang violence.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 1, no. 1), 1991 October (Box 6)
    Ice Cube
    Marley Marl, Tragedy, Yo-Yo, Young Black Teenagers, Fonke Socialistiks, John Singleton, Gerardo, Bytches with Problems, DJ Quik, Ice-T, Sampling, Hoes Wit Attitude.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 1, no. 2), 1991 December (Box 6)
    3rd Bass
    Hank Shocklee, Overwieght Pooch, 3rd Bass, Are Major Record Companies Destroying Rap?, Nikki-D, On the Set of Alwayz into Something, Redhead Kingpin & The FBI Tribe, Isis, WC & Madd Circle, YZ.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 1, no. 3), 1992 February (Box 6)
    Dee Barnes
    Record producer Sir Jinx, Dee Barnes, Chuck D, Black Sheep, Sister Souljah, Cypress Hill, C&C Music Factory's Freedom Williams, Queen Mother Rage (X-Clan), Raw Fusion.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 1, no. 6), 1992 August (Box 6)
    Eric B & Rakim
    Easy Mo Bee, AMG, Eric B & Rakim, Too Short, Paris, rhythym poets The Watts Brothers, Pete Rock & CL Smooth, A Tribe Called Quest's Young Griot.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 1, no. 8), 1992 December (Box 6)
    EPMD & EFX
    City-to-City Tour of hip-hop (New York, L.A., Atlanta, Houston, the Bay Area), Ice Cube, Grand Puba, EPMD & Das EFX, Speech Speaks on the African Connection.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 1, no. 9), 1992 February (Box 6)
    Eazy E
    DJ/Mixmaster Muggs, Agenda '93: What Y'all Gon' Do?, MC Serch, Eazy E, female rap duo The Boss, NWH (Niggas Wit' Hats), Gang Starr, Run-DMC.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 2, no. 5), 1993 June (Box 6)
    Ed Lover and Dr. Dre
    Producer/rapper Large Professor, Dr. Dre, Hip-Hop & Hollywood, Ed Lover and Doctor Dre, Tupac, Latifah; Crazy Legs, Wiggles & Gremlin on Hip-Hop Dance; the Hughes Brothers, Rap on TV.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 2, no. 6), 1993 July (Box 6)
    Producer DJ Pooh, Compton's Most Wanted's MC Eiht, Above the Law's Cold 187um, Sunshine People: LA's New School, Snoop Doggy Dogg, Groups That Shoulda Blown Up But Didn't, King Tee, Hieroglyphics, Ice-T, Lowriders.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 2, no. 8), 1993 October (Box 6)
    DJ Magic Mike
    Organized Konfusion, Biz Markie, Ultramagnetic MCs, DJ Magic Mike, Funkdoobiest, YoYo, Cypress Hill, Fall Fashion Preview.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 2, no. 9), 1993 November (Box 6)
    Scarface
    Producer QDIII, Kam, Alkaholiks, Knuclehedz, West Coast Rap Scene, Scarface, lyricist/rapper Threat, The Black Panthers, Party of the People, EPMD's Erick Sermon, MC Lyte.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 3, no. 5), 1994 June (Box 6)
    MC Eiht of Compton's Most Wanted
    Producers from A Tribe Called Quest, The Roots, MC Eiht, Whodini, Gang Starr, Kurious, Beastie Boys.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 3, no. 6), 1994 August (Box 6)
    Notorious B.I.G.
    Houston's Odd Squad, Notorious B.I.G., Kokane, House Of Pain, Anti Fashion, Pro Style: Gear Does Not Hip-Hop Make, Summer Sounds '94.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 3, no. 7), 1994 September (Box 6)
    Conscious Daughters, Pete Rock and CL Smooth, OutKast, Ahmad, Big Mike, EPMD, Dred Scott, Rap, Race & Reality: Injustice for All.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 3, no. 8), 1994 November (Box 6)
    E-40
    Saafir, Playaz in the Game: The Bay Area Blows Up, Organized Konfusion, Ill All Skratch, King Just, Smif-n-Wessun.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 3, no. 9), 1994 December (Box 6)
    The L.A. Underground (Sin, Medusa, Koko, Erule, Ras Kass, Ganjah K, Aceyalone), Uncle Jam's Army Relives Its Glory Days, Vida En La Cruz: Life on the Cross, Remembering KDAY: L.A.'s Rap Radio Days.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 4, no. 7), 1995 August (Box 6)
    Remembering Eazy-E
    Ghetto Beach: Summer Fashion Preview, Mobb Deep, African Martial Arts, Eric "Eazy-E" Wright."
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 4, no. 8), 1995 September (Box 6)
    Kool G Rap
    Aceyalone, Luniz, Dayton Family, Grand Puba, Kool G Rap, Mad CJ Mac.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 4, no. 11), 1995 December (Box 6)
    Biggie Smalls, Coolio, Snoop Doggy Dogg, the Fugees, the Pharcycle, F. Gary Gray, Raekwon, Johnnie Cochran, Time Warner Cuts Interscope Ties.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 5, no. 2), 1996 March (Box 6)
    Kwest Tha Madd Lad
    Suga T, Project Hope, Kwest Tha Madd Lad, Luke (Luther Campbell), Smoothe Da Hustler, KRS-One/Graffiti, soul singer L.V., female rapper Bahamadia.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 5, no. 3), 1996 April (Box 6)
    DJ Premier
    DJ Premier, DJ Roundtables (featuring Kool Herc, Afrika Bambaataa, Grandwizard Theodore, Charlie Chase, DJ LaSpank, Q-Bert, Shortkut, Disk, Apollo, and the Beat Junkie), Turntable Tech-know-logy, Rap in Philadelphia, Science of the Blend (about mixtapes).
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 5, no. 5), 1996 June (Box 6)
    Sanyika Shakur
    Sanyika Shakur, The Destruction of Hip-Hop 1970-2020, Ronnie Brown, Privatized prisons, Devils Work: Just What Are Those Darn Republicans Up To?
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 5, no. 9) (Special 5th Birthday Issue, 1996 October (Box 6)
    Rap Pages' Best Covers, In Rap-trospect, Above the Law, Willie Hutch, Foxxy Brown, Ras Kass, Innovation Hinges on the Fringes, A History of Hardcore Instrumental Hip-Hop.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 6, no. 9), 1997 October (Box 7)
    Sean Puffy Combs
    Jay-Z, Puff Daddy, House of Blues Smokin' Grooves tour, Beatnuts.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 8, no. 3), 1999 March (Box 7)
    Method Man, Nonchalant, Xenon, DJ Quik, Trick Daddy, The Roots, Digital Underground, Total.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 8, no. 5), 1999 May (Box 7)
    Redman, Scarface, Naughty by Nature, Rap-a-Lot, Houston artists, Prince Paul, Harlem World.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 8, no. 9), 1999 September (Box 7)
    Mobb Deep
    Mobb Deep, Made Men, Bridge People (interviews with homeless people), Del the Funkee Homosapien, Hard Knock Life Tour, Darlene, Terror Squad, Chuck D, MC Eiht.
  - Rap Pages/RapPages (Bi-monthly) (vol. 8, no. 10), 1999 October (Box 7)
    Fiend
    Fiend, Spice, Lydia Harris, Sway & King Tech, Mr. Cartoon, Sheppard Lane, Kool Keith, The Beatnuts, Rap City (BET program).
  - Rap Sheet (Premiere Issue), 1992 July (Box 8)
    DJ Quik
    Hardcore soul from DJ Quik, Eazy-E, L.A. Riots, Evolution of hardcore lyrics, Cypress Hill, Lifers Group, X-rated rapper Luke vs. Luther the Businessman.
  - Rap Sheet, 1992 September (Box 8)
    Chubb Rock
    On the 3R's: Rap, Rock & Racism; Hip Hop Heavies (acid jazz meets hip hop); Shabba and Supercat on relationship between rap and reggae; Roxanne; Guns Aren't Sexy: Face to Face with Chubb Rock; Aerosol Art; Indie Label Series: Mack 4 Business (Sir Mix-a-Lot talks about his Rhyme Cartel).
  - Rap Sheet, 1992 October (Box 8)
    Rakim
    MC Serch, Poor Righteous Teachers (the 85, the 10 and the 5 percent nation), Hammer The Holy Ghost Boy (plus Christian rappers), Rakim, Pete Rock and CL Smooth, Afrika Bambaata.
  - Rap Sheet, 1992 December (Box 8)
    Chuck D
    LL Cool J, Rap and Radio, Trippin' on the Remix, Single Success Stories, College radio, EPMD and Run-DMC on bringing hip hop up from the underground, Chuck D: How Black is urban radio?, LL and his Cut-Creators (LL Cool J, Bobcat, and Marley Marl).
  - Rap Sheet, 1993 March (Box 8)
    N.W.A.
    Above the Law, Enemies 4 Life or Appetite for Reunion?: Cube, Eazy, Dre, Ren, Griff.
  - Rap Sheet, 1993 October (Box 8)
    Nikki D: Stepping to Bitch Ass Men; Queen Latifah and Flavor Unit; Flavor Unit Posse: Nikki D, Apache, Fu-Schnickens; New Jacks to the Flavor Unit Crew (Brooklyn Assault Team, Bigga Sisters, Groove Garden, Freddie Foxxx, Leshaun); Special Editorial: Just another day in the life of young Black men in Amerikka (about police brutality).
  - Rap Sheet, 1993 December (Box 8)
    Fat Joe
    Hip Hop Latino Style, Fat Joe, Funkdoobiest and Soul Assassins, Kid Frost, Rock Steady Crew, O.M.D., Lighter Shade of Brown.
  - Rap Sheet, 1994 February (Box 8)
    Eazy-E: The real Compton City "G"; What to check for in '94 - special preview issue; F@#k the Grammys; A Tribe Called Quest; Guns, Violence and hip hop.
  - Rap Sheet (Women of Rap Special Edition), 1994 June (Box 8)
    Salt-n-Pepa
    Salt-n-Pepa: hip hop's feminine flavor; SimplēE: The Sugar Hill cool cat who reigns supreme; Special Report: Mistresses and Princesses, the new breed of female emcees featuring Conscious Daughters, the Lady of Rage, Brat, Champ MC, Grip and Sha-Key; Ice-T editorial on Tony Bogart and L.A. gangs.
  - Rap Sheet (Special Rap-a-Lot Records Issue), 1994 July (Box 8)
    Geto Boys
    The Youngest of the Wu-Tang: Shyheim the rugged child; Geto Boys; Russell Simmons; 5IVe-O; James Smith; Shyheim; Hottest Houston hip hop; Day in the Hood: Rolling through Houston with Odd Squad and 5th Ward Boyz.
  - Rap Sheet (vol. 2, no. 8) (Def Jam Records Special Issue), 1994 August (Box 8)
    G-Funk drama: the plot thickens with Warren G; Public Enemy; UJIMA: KRS-One explains the Stop the Violence Movement.
  - Rap Sheet (vol. 2, no. 9), 1994 September (Box 8)
    Jeru tha Damaja
    Best of the East: Does New York still have it?, Mecca and the Soul Brother (Pete Rock and C.L. Smooth), Jeru tha Damaja, Black Owned (Jam Master Jay and JMJ Records).
  - Rap Sheet (vol. 2, no. 10), 1994 October (Box 8)
    Eazy-E